Guide to the Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations
2007-ongoing
WEB.ARC.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
825.0 websites
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations, established in 2007 in conjunction with the California Digital Library’s Web Archiving Service (WAS), contains webpages of organizations and other entities concerned with issues related to economic, civil, and social justice from a left and/or progressive perspective. These entities focus on issues ranging from corporate accountability, immigrant rights, unemployment, homelessness, urban justice, healthcare reform, wealth redistribution, and other issues, including a focus on the Occupy Wall Street movement and the Guantanamo Detention Camp. Tamiment also archives political websites, focusing on political parties of the far Left, including Marxists, Communists, Socialists, and Trotskyists. Website contain a variety of formats and materials, including pdfs, images, multimedia, event listings, and blogs.
Tamiment Library.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library Web Collection on Organizations, first began by Tamiment in 2007, contains webpages of organizations and other entities concerned with issues related to economic, civil, and social justice from a left and/or progressive perspective. This is an assembled collection, the websites were selected by the archivists. These entities focus on issues ranging from corporate accountability, immigrant rights, unemployment, homelessness, urban justice, healthcare reform, wealth redistribution, and other issues. The collection also contains websites related to environmental and green movements, prisoner rights, the Jewish American Left, peace movements, art and cultural organizations, education and youth movements, animal rights, feminism, housing rights, and other websites related to the Left movement. Tamiment also archives political websites, focusing on Marxian inspired entities, including political parties that identify with or are inspired by Communist, Socialist, or Trotskyist perspectives.
In addition, there is a huge focus in this collection on the Occupy Wall Street Movement, established in September 2011. Occupy Wall Street is a social movement, started in New York City, that works to reform both the private and public sector. The websites in the collection focus on different aspects and working groups of the movement. Another huge focus of the collection contains websites of those critical of U.S. policy in relation to Guantanamo Detention Camp and its representation governing enemy combatants, prisoner interrogation, the related legal processes and issues, the global detention system established by the Bush administration, including efforts to secure civil and human rights for detainees. Contents include prisoners' testimony and documents from attorneys defending them.
These websites contain a huge variety of media, which include videos, pdfs, blog postings (including Tumblr and Wordpress blogs), petitions, news feeds, message boards (or forums), and audio. These websites often act to document and update upon the organizations’ activities, schedule upcoming events, build awareness of their cause or organization, information on projects the organizations are working on, writings and articles by members of the organization or party, or other activities.
The web collection documents the publicly available content of the web page, it does not archive material that is password protected or blocked due to robot txt exclusions. Although Tamiment attempts to archive the entirety of a website, certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (Youtube, Vimeo, or otherwise), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site.
Arrangement
Websites are arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Tamiment Library, New York University began web archiving in 2007 as part of a grant given by the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program (NDIPP) of the Library of Congress. As most unions, left movements, progressive organizations, and others stop creating ephemeral material and paper based collections and move most of their administrative and informational material to the web, Tamiment continued to document the changing face of the labor and left movement into the web era. Tamiment uses the California Digital Library’s Web Archiving Service (WAS) as their tool to capture and preserve websites. WAS was created in 2007 and Tamiment is one of its earliest partners. The California Digital Library provides the storage and infrastructure for the project.
Access Restrictions
Archived websites are open to researchers without restrictions. Archived websites are made publically available 6 months after the initial capture.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. This can include videos (including Youtube and Vimeo), pdfs (including Scribd or another pdf reader), rss feeds/plug-ins (including Twitter), commenting platforms (disqus, Facebook), presi, images, or anything that is not native to the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Robot txt exclusions also change the formatting of websites from their original display, websites with robot txt exclusions often display as an index.
Keyword and file-type search are also available to archived websites through the Web Archiving Service (WAS). To search for keywords within archived websites, click a site name link in the container list. From that page, click the "search" tab on the top left corner. From the search page, you can search by keyword, URL, and file type across all captures of one site or all the sites in the project.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Websites are selected by archivists and captured through the use of the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service (WAS). WAS uses a web crawler to copy the website at a scheduled time and displays only an archived copy of the website.
Accruals note
In general, crawls of sites are added quarterly. New sites are added to finding aids upon completion of 6 month embargo.
Related Archival Materials
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Individuals
Tamiment Library Web Collection on Labor Unions
Printed Ephemera Collection on Organizations (PE 036)
Existence and Location of Originals note
Clicking on the links provided in the container list will take the user to the Web Archiving Service (WAS) page for the website. Sometimes the original website is still available on the live web and the original URL may be available. To get to the original web page, click the live link provided in the "Latest Starting URL" field on the WAS page.
Take Down Policy
Tamiment respects robot txt exclusions and requests from websites with robot txt exclusions to allow our crawler to capture their website. Tamiment will also honor the website owner’s request to remove their website from the collection. To request a site removal, please contact tamiment.wagner@library.nyu.edu
Alternative mass media.; Anarchism |z United States.; Civil rights.; Communism |z United States.; Environmentalism.; Feminism.; Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp.; Housing |z New York (State) |z New York.; Jewish radicals.; New York (N.Y.); News web sites |z United States.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Peace movements.; Protest movements.; Socialism.; Web portals.
- #occupywallstreet Archived Website, Oct 25, 2011- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
  Scope and Contents note
  #occupywallstreet is a tumblr blog that contains updates related to the September 17, 2011 occupation of Wall Street by New York City protestors. The website contains news, audiovisual media, and other articles.
  Distributive justice.; Financial sector of the American economy.; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).; Social responsibility of business.
- #S17NYC Archived Website, Sep 15, 2012-Oct 4, 2012; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
  This website is the call to action for the Occupy Wall Street movement’s September 17, 2012 event, to commemorate the first anniversary of Occupy Wall Street. The event was a four day event made up of assemblies, concerts, talks, and other programs. The website contains a schedule, multimedia, a news blog, and outreach materials.
  Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- 100 Days to Close Guantánamo and End Torture Archived Website, Aug 2, 2009-Mar 17, 2010; 100 Days to Close Guantanamo & End Torture.
  We support President Obama's executive order to close the Guantanamo prison. But it must be closed not just on paper, but in reality. After seven years of detaining hundreds of men without trial, a one year timeline for closing Guantanamo is unacceptable. For the over 70 men currently on hunger strike in Guantanamo, it has been seven years too long. We want justice now. Witness Against Torture announces a campaign to close the U.S. detention facilities at Guantanamo Bay, Cuba, and end torture and rendition by the U.S. within the first 100 days of the new administration. With Barack Obama taking office, we have a historic opportunity to reverse the disastrous policies of the last eight years.
  Guantánamo Bay Detention Camp.; Iraq War, 2003-2011 |x Prisoners and prisons, American.; Torture |z United States.
- 123 Community Space Archived Website, Feb 20, 2009-Jul 7, 2011; 123 Community Space.
  123 was a community space in the Bedford-Stuyvesant neighborhood of Brooklyn that was formed by formed by four grassroots groups - A New World In Our Hearts, Freegan Bike Workshop, Misled Youth Network, NYC Anarchist Black Cross. The organization held daily programs, had a screen-printing studio, a food co-op, a lending library, and support groups. The goal of 123 was to create a community center for the people of Bed-Stuy to organize and make their voices heard. 123 closed down in 2009.
  Anarchism |z New York (State) |z New York.; Bedford-Stuyvesant (New York, N.Y.) |x Social conditions.; Community organization |z New York (State) |z New York.
- 15th october: #United we will re-invent the world Archived Website, Oct 28, 2011-Dec 1, 2011; United for Global Change
  An international website to raise support internationally for the Occupy Movement. The website contains information on global actions that took place in October 2011.
- 3.11 ACTION NYC Archived Website, Mar 9, 2013- ongoing; 3.11 Action New York
  3.11 Action New York is the website for a march in New York City planned on March 11, 2012. March 11 marks the anniversary of the tsunami in Japan, which triggered the Fukushima Daiichi nuclear accident. The march is an anti-nuclear energy campaign.
  Antinuclear movement.
- 350.org Archived Website, Jul 13, 2011- ongoing; 350.org
  350.org is a grassroots movement that works to solve the climate crisis through organizing online campaigns and mass public actions. 350.org raises awareness and works to reduce the amount of carbon dioxide in the atmosphere from its current level at 392 parts per million (ppm) to 350 ppm.
  Climate change.; Global warming |x Prevention.
- 99% Power, People's Rights Over Corporate Wrongs Archived Website, Dec 4, 2012-Jun 1, 2014; 99% Power, People's Rights Over Corporate Wrongs
  The 99 Power: People’s Rights over Corporate Wrongs was a grassroots campaign, established in Spring 2012, united to build a new economy and democracy. The campaign called for nonviolent direct action against corporations, including Wells Fargo, GE, Verizon, Sallie Mae, Wal-Mart, Bank of America, and Verizon. The coalition that sponsored this campaign included unions, environmental groups, and other social justice organizations.
  Corporate accountability.; Social responsibility of business.
- 99 Pickets Archived Website, Sep 23, 2012- ongoing; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
  99 Pickets, a working group from Occupy Wall Street, works to build the worker's movement in New York City using picket lines. The website contains a blog, action alerts, campaigns, and organizational information.
- A.J. Muste Memorial Institute Archived Website, Dec 23, 2008- ongoing; A.J. Muste Memorial Institute.
  The A.J. Muste Memorial Institute is a nonprofit charitable foundation established in 1974 to honor the legacy of pacifist leader A.J. Muste (1885-1967) and to further nonviolent action as the means to achieve social and economic justice. They provide grants, resources and a wide range of support to activist organizations that use nonviolent strategies to oppose war and promote justice and by publishing and distributing educational materials about nonviolence. The website contains publications and information on grants and scholarships.
  Charities |z United States.; Pacifism--United States.; Peace movements |z United States.
- ABC No Rio Archived Website, Feb 8, 2007 - ongoing; ABC No Rio
  ABC No Rio was founded in 1980 by artists committed to political and social engagement in the Lower East Side. It is a collectively-run center for art and activism, and features a gallery space, a zine library, a darkroom, a silkscreening studio, and public computer lab. ABC No Rio seeks to be a community center for the Lower East Side, hosting and sponsoring projects and benefits for the community, promoting volunteerism, art and activism, without giving-in to corporate sponsors.
  Art |x Political aspects.; Artists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Hispanic Americans |z New York (State) |z New York.; Lower East Side (New York, N.Y.).
- Abolition 2000 Archived Website, Jul 12, 2011- ongoing; Abolition 2000
  ABOLITION 2000, founded in 1995, is a network of over 2000 organizations in more than 90 countries working for a global treaty to eliminate nuclear weapons within a time-bound framework. The Network aims at providing groups concerned with nuclear issues a forum for the exchange of information and the development of joint initiatives. The Abolition 2000 Network meets once a year and communicates on an ongoing basis via list serves, conferences, teleconferencing, and periodic mailings. The website contains information on member organizations, working groups, and information on conferences.
  Antinuclear movement.; Nuclear disarmament.
- Abolition of Speciesism Archived Website, Aug 11, 2010-Aug 11, 2011; Abolition of Specieism
  The Abolitionism of Specieism’s main goals are to provide a clear statement of a nonviolent approach to animal rights that require the abolition of animal exploitation, animals rights based upon only animal sentience and no other cognitive characteristic, and regards veganism as the moral baseline of the animal rights position.
  Animal rights activists.; Animal rights.; Veganism; Vegans
- Abortion Clinic Defense Archived Website, Apr 24, 2013-Jul 23, 2013; Abortion Clinic Defense
  Abortion Clinic Defense is a tumblr blog that operates as a news source and support group for individuals defending abortion clinics from agitators. The website contains resources.
  Abortion rights movement.; Pro-choice movement |z United States.; Reproductive rights |z United States.
- Abraham Lincoln Brigade: Spanish Civil War History and Education: Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives Archived Website, Feb 8, 2007 - ongoing; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives.
  The Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives (ALBA) is dedicated to preserving and communicating the history and memory of those Americans who participated in the Spanish Civil War on the Republican side. It is also successor to the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade. The ALBA archives are housed at the Tamiment Library, New York University. They also publish the quarterly journal, The Volunteer.
- Access: Mobilizing for Global Digital Freedom Archived Website, Mar 7, 2011- ongoing; Access
  Founded in 2009, Access is a non-profit organization premised on the belief that the realization of human rights and democracy in the twenty-first century is increasingly predicated on access to the internet and other forms of information communication technology. Access unites with digital activists and civil society groups internationally to build their technical capacity and to help them advocate globally for their digital rights and provides thought leadership and practical policy recommendations in the broader field of internet freedom, and based on that expertise mobilizes its global movement of citizens to campaign for an open internet accessible to all. Access publishes news related to internet censorship and other campaigns.
  Freedom of information.; Information, computer, communications policy.; Internet |x Law and legislation.
- Access Strategies Fund Archived Website, May 11, 2012- ongoing; Access Strategies Fund
  Access Strategies Fund is a philanthropic foundation that supports organizations fighting for social justice and expanding the democratic process within underserved communities. They provide training and support for infrastructure to help overcome organizational barriers and build partnerships. The website contains information about funding, programs, news, and resources.
  Endowments.; Social justice.
- ACORN Archived Website, Nov 20, 2008-Mar 12, 2012; ACORN (Organization)
  The Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN), formed in 1970, was a collection of community-based organizations in the United States that advocated for low- and moderate-income families by working on neighborhood safety, voter registration, health care, affordable housing, and other social issues. In 2010, ACORN filed Chapter 7 liquidation and closed the organization. The organization consisted of 400,000 member families organized into more than 1,200 neighborhood chapters in 110 cities across the country.organizations that are committed to social and economic justice, and won victories on thousands of issues of concern to our members, through direct action, negotiation, legislative advocacy and voter participation. ACORN helps those who have historically been locked out become powerful players in our democratic system.
  Community organization |z United States.
- Act Against Torture Archived Website, Aug 1, 2009-Feb 8, 2010; Act Against Torture.
  Act Against Torture is a coalition of activists based in the San Francisco Bay Area working to abolish torture and indefinite detention, to end U.S. intervention in Iraq and Afghanistan, and to prevent future wars. Our work is guided by radical, systemic analysis of war, torture and detention; the connections between these and other forms of oppression are the reason we support other movements for social justice as an integral part of our mission. We use strategic, campaign-based organizing to link individual actions in pusuit of larger goals. We work to build strong coalitions and are committed to democratic and participatory organizing. Act Against Torture is not affiliated with any party or organization.
- Action Resource Fund Archived Website, May 4, 2013-Nov 2, 2013; Action Resource Fund
  The Action Resource Fund (ARF), formerly known as the May Day Fundraising Affinity Group, is a collection of Occupy Activists who joined together to fund raise for protests and actions. ARF raised funds for MayDay 2012- 2013 actions, as well as raise money for those affected by Hurricane Sandy in the fall of 2012. The website contains fundraising reports and a blog.
  Fund raising.; Hurricane Sandy, 2012.; May Day (Labor holiday).; Occupy Wall Street (Movement).
- Activist Poet's Roundtable with Dennis Brutus | The Socialist Party - USA, Greater NYC Local Archived Website, May 2, 2011; Activist Poets' Roundtable
  Activist Poets’ Roundtable with Dennis Brutus was an event in New York City on March 16, 2008. Dennis Brutus was a banned poet and political prisoner on Robben Island with Nelson Mandela and 1000 others before the fall of Apartheid in South Africa.
  Political poetry.
- Act Now to Stop War and End Racism (ANSWER) Archived Website, Aug 17, 2009- ongoing; A.N.S.W.E.R. Coalition.
  Act Now to Stop War and End Racism (ANSWER), was formed on September 14, 2001. ANSWER is a coalition of organizations and individuals across the United States, campaigning against US intervention in Latin America, the Carribbean, the Middle East and Asia. Partner organizations have campaigned for civil rights and for social and economic justice for working and poor people inside the United States. They work through direct action, protests, and other forms of demonstration. The website contains news listings, news analysis, information about regional offices, and event listings.
  Anti-imperialist movements |z United States.; Social justice |z United States.; Trotskyism |z United States.
- Act Up New York Archived Website, Dec 7, 2008 - ongoing; ACT UP New York (Organization).
  Act Up NY was founded in New York City in 1987 and is a diverse, non-partisan group of individuals united in anger and committed to direct action to end the AIDS crisis. AIDS Coalition to Unleash Power (ACT UP), founded in New York City in 1987, and is a diverse, non-partisan group committed to direct action to end the AIDS crisis by bringing about legislation, medical research, treatment, and policies to bring an end to the disease. The website has not been updated since 2007.
  AIDS activists |z New York (State) |z New York.; Gay liberation movement |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Adbusters Culturejammer Headquarters Archived Website, Nov 28, 2010- ongoing; Adbusters Media Foundation
  Based in Vancouver, British Columbia, Canada, Adbusters Media Foundation is a not-for-profit, reader-supported, magazine concerned about the erosion of our physical and cultural environments by commercial forces. Adbusters offers philosophical articles as well as activist commentary from around the world addressing issues ranging from genetically modified foods to media concentration. Adbusters is an ecological magazine, dedicated to examining the relationship between human beings and their physical and mental environment. The website is made up of back issues of the magazine, spoof ads, blogs, and videos.
  Advertising |x Political aspects.; Political satire.; Social satire.
- Aesthetic Realism Foundation Archived Website, Jun 3, 2012 - ongoing; Aesthetic Realism Foundation
  The Aesthetic Realism Foundation’s goal “is to meet the urgent need for people throughout America and the world to see each other and reality fairly” based on Eli Siegel’s philosophy. The Foundation offers classes every semester, workshops, public seminars, outreach programs, and consultations. The foundation also supports a theatre company and gallery. The website contains information on Eli Siegel, their programs, library, and other resources on aesthetic realism.
  Aesthetics.
- AFT ACTS Archived Website, May 1, 2011- ongoing; Alliance of Charter Teachers and Staff
  The Alliance of Charter Teachers and Staff (ACTS) is community of charter school employees organized by the Federation of Teachers. The alliance works to mobilize charter school employees around issues such as expanding professional development, bettering wages and benefits, improving teaching and learning conditions, and strengthening their voice in school-level decision making.
  Charter schools |z United States.
- Against Child Trafficking (ACT) Archived Website, Dec 15, 2009- ongoing; Against Child Trafficking